# Ming Shun Kwek

#### Software Student

Address Singapore, Singapore

**Phone** (+65) 8125 9299

**E-mail** mingshun1998@hotmail.com

**LinkedIn** www.linkedin.com/in/kwek-ming-shun https://github.com/MingShun98 https://mingshun98.github.io/Portfolio-Website/

Currently a year 3 computer engineering student studying at National University of Singapore. Clear communicator and determine in tasks I set my mind too. Forward-thinking development professional bringing expertise in Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and other programming languages. Diligently learning everything I can, gaining more experience in different fields so that one day, I could contribute more towards the world of technology.

#### **Skills**

Object-Oriented Programming

Effective Communication for Computing Professionals

Data Structures and Algorithms

Code versioning

Functional Specification documentation

Mobile/ Web Development

## **Work History**

#### 2021-06 - 2022-02

## Java Software Developer

Integro Technologies Pte Ltd

- Troubleshot various software issues by using debugging processes and coding techniques.
- Investigated issues and defects to determine problem root cause and formulate corrective action recommendations, successfully resolving over 30 issues.
- Wrote, modified and maintained software documentation and specifications.

#### 2019-11 - 2020-08

## **Head of Programmes**

NUS Raffles Hall Freshmen Orientation Camp

 Coordinated sequence of programmes for 200 freshmen, while maintaining communication across multiple departments to ensure smooth operation while clarifying conflicting ideas. • Spearheading team of 10, like-minded individuals while resolve conflicting visions, guiding innovation towards enhancing event flow.

#### 2020-05 - 2020-07 Software Development

NUS Orbital Programme

- Developed SmartTrack savings application in React Native that aids in budget management with additional features that ease expense sharing with other users.
- Achieved Apollo 11 (advanced) standard certification, determined to have demonstrated awareness of basics in software engineering, testing and documentation.
- Picked up relevant software development skills and knowledge like Javascript and Google Firebase API.

#### 2018-11 - 2019-06 Contracts/Projects Assistant

YL Integrated PTE LTD

- Analyzed and calculated required lighting and fire emergency equipment in floor plans for tender projects, necessary for purchase and installation.
- Managed contact between suppliers and company, answering inquires regarding quotations as well as purchase orders.
- Managed and mentored team of 3 employees, overseeing training, and professional growth of employees.

## 2017-08 - 2018-11 Sergeant, 1st Battalion Singapore Guards

Singapore Armed Forces (National Service)

- Planned for mission objectives and engaging in discussions with full time servicemen to better optimized battle plans and efficient routes for mission success.
- Facilitated 30+ recruits as an instructor, teaching and mentoring enlistees, later transitioned into leader role after recruits graduated from Basic Training and thereafter, being responsible for them during active service.

## **Education**

## 2019-08 - Current Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Engineering

National University of Singapore

• GPA: 4.05/5.00

• Expected Graduation: July 2023

## 2015-01 - 2016-12 High School Diploma

Nanyang Junior College

Achieved 78.75 RP with 2 H2 Distinctions in Chemistry and Mathematics.

# Languages

English

Mandarin Chinese

## Software

Java Programming

C++ Programming

HTML/ CSS / JavaScript

C Programming

Git/ Github

Python

SQL